# Grishan Artem

☑ artemgris66@gmail.com | 🛅 linkedin.com/in/legendaryoper/

## Summary.

Experienced Software Engineer(Backend) with more than 2 years of commercial experience in developing and maintaining high-quality software applications. Strong problem-solving and analytical skills with a passion for writing clean, efficient, and maintainable code. Has experience working with clients from different locations and industries. Committed to delivering high-quality solutions that meet the needs of clients. Also has experience with leading, mentoring, code-review, new developers onboarding. Worked in domains such as SaaS, Logistics, ERP, and Educational.

## Work Experience

Innowise Group Belarus, Minsk

Software Engineer

June 2022 - Current

- Worked in outsourcing company on various projects
- · Developed high-loaded, scalable and reliable REST and serverless API's
- Split old monolithic architecture to microservices
- · Database schema design and implementation. Worked with triggers, raw SQL queries, indexes
- Designed, implemented and maintained cloud architecture
- Set up Kafka broker on AWS for serverless part triggering
- Implemented Filesystem microservice using lambda functions
- Made our services async
- · DynamoDB setting up and integration
- AWS Redshift queries optimization
- · Statistics microservice implementation from scratch
- · Communicated and collaborated with clients to understand their requirements and deliver solutions that met their needs
- Implemented CI/CD mechanism using CircleCI
- · Leading, Mentoring
- Code-review for other backend developers on projects
- Kubernetes integration testing using MiniKube
- Technical Skills: Python, SQL, Django, Django REST Framework, AWS, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, DynamoDB, FastAPI, AsyncIO, AioHTTP, Celery, Redis, Docker, Docker-compose, RabbitMQ, Kafka, CI/CD, CircleCI

MusicGYM London, Great Britain(Remote)

Software Engineer

September 2021 - May 2022

- Worked as Backend developer in a product company, mainly on Flask/MariaDB stack
- Developed and maintained REST API
- Migrated responsibility from SQL to NoSQL DB
- Developed payment microservice from scratch using Flask and Stripe
- Developed exams microservice from scratch
- Designed cloud infrastructure
- Monitored and maintained cloud
- Prevented security breaches using AWS EC2 VPC and security groups
- Integrated exams microservice with AI to prevent cheating
- Set up microservices communication using RabbitMQ
- · Solved an issue with videos translation on Alibaba Cloud
- Implemented deploy scripts on various servers with bash-scripting
- Technical Skills: Flask, Stripe, MariaDB, Redis, RabbitMQ, MongoDB, AWS, Alibaba cloud, docker, docker-compose, Nginx, Apache, bash-scripting

**Upwork** Remote

#### Freelance Software Engineer

February 2021 - September 2021

- Fullstack development
- Implemented automation/chat bots from scratch
- Database optimization, schema design
- Web applications development for small businesses.
- Telephone calls redirection REST API development from scratch.
- · Web applications hosting and monitoring.
- Tech Skills: Python, SQL, Django, Django REST Framework, Celery, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, VPS/VDS, pyTelegramBotAPI, Git, MySQL, Redis, Docker, Docker-compose

### **Education**

#### **Minsk Radioengineering College**

Minsk, Belarus

Computer Science and Software Engineering

· MSc in Computer Science and Software Engineering